好
All right.
到20英里了吗
That's 20?
快了  还有1英里就到642号公路了
It will be. 642 is a mile ahead.
我们得在岔道前跟它们拉开距离
We gotta put distance between us and them before the turnoff.
加速吧
So floor it.
好  努力跟上
All right, try to keep up.
达里尔  你看过这辆车吗
Daryl, have you looked at this car?
相信我  我们也想尽快回去的
Believe me, we want to get back there, too.
别管了
Leave it.
我打算最后给它"美化"一下
Just gonna give it a last little polish.
你笑什么呢
What the hell you got to grin about?
我们赢了  亲爱的
We won, darlin'.
可能还有更多人
There could be more.
算了
Screw it.
《行尸走肉》
萨沙
Sasha?
亚伯拉罕  你在吗
Abraham, are you there?
你找到我们了  好吗
You found us, okay?
我们在这里
Here we are.
我们拿走的都是应得的
We earned what we took.
也许只是某个前哨站的一个士兵
Probably just another soldier from one of the outposts.
也许也讨厌他
Probably hates him, too.
你知道怎么用吗
You know how to use one?
知道
Yeah.
从来不喜欢用这东西捕猎
Never liked using them to hunt.
我们去接帕蒂  然后就走  好吗
We pick up Patty and we're gone, okay?
这是我们最后一天这样过活了
This is the last day we gotta live like this.
起来
Get up.
Hey, get up.
我们要走了  是这样的
We're moving. Here's the deal.
你不说话  我就不杀你
You don't say shit and I don't kill you.
我不是你以为的人
I ain't who you think.
再说一句试试
Say something else.
说啊
Go ahead.
跟着她们
Follow them.
给  喝了剩下的
Here, drink the rest.
-我们该省着喝  -我们会找到更多的水
- We should save it. - We'll find some more.
喝了吧
Drink.
你该保持水分
You're supposed to stay hydrated.
一切都会好的
It all works together.
是啊
Yeah, it does.
喝吧
Have it.
我们不能让你倒下
We don't need you falling down.
喝
Drink.
如果他们找到我们  也许我们会交出你
They find us, maybe we give you to them,
这样就扯平了
they let us call it even.
我们是讲理的人
You see, we're reasonable people.
大家都有自己的原则
Everybody's got their code.
你愿意下跪  那可以
You feel you gotta kneel, that's fair enough.
我们不愿意
We don't.
走吧
Let's go.
不敢相信我们回来了
I can't believe we're back.
这里不再是家了
It's not home anymore,
但总比我们之前待的地方好
but it's better than where we were.
只在这里停留一下
This is a pit stop.
我们接走帕蒂  仅此而已
We pick up Patty, nothing more than that.
你们是怎么做的
How'd you do it?
你看见我们停卡车的地方了吧
You saw where we left the truck?
我们把汽油阀门打开了
We opened the valve
从农景路一路开过来
and drove all the way in from Farmview Road.
在树林里穿梭  直到我们开上路面
Ran from the tree line till we got to the pavement.
点燃了从斯威特沃特拿来的纸板火柴
Lit up a matchbook from the Sweetwater
把它扔到油迹上
and dropped it in on the trail.
然后我们冲向车子
Then we just ran for the car.
爬了进去  车边全是行尸
Got in and the dead ones were there.
它们撞在引擎盖上  然后...
They were beating on the hood, and then--
然后  "轰"
and then boom!
它们全翻了
Knocked 'em on their asses
然后我再用斧子一个个解决了
and I took an axe to each one.
然后我们就看着火焰渐起
Then we just watched it go up.
再也听不见那些吼声和哀嚎
No more moans, no more of that wailing.
只有大火在燃烧  将它们全部烧成灰烬
It was just the fire, just burning them all away.
这都是你们干的吗
You did all this?
当时一切才刚刚开始
It was right at the start.
一切都停了  电视  广播
Everything stopped-- the TV, the radio.
我们就在这里  树林里全是行尸
We were here. The forest was full of them.
城里的行尸也被吸引了过来
And the other ones in town, they were drawn to it.
径直走进了火中
They just walked right into the flames.
我们干掉了它们中的大部分
We got most of them.
以为我们这边搞定了
Thought we ended it for us,
而她当时在华盛顿
and she was in DC.
我们以为无论在哪里  大家都在和它们抗争
We thought everyone was fighting them wherever they were.
是啊  我们以为大家都在这样做
Yeah, we thought that was what everybody was doing.
在抗争它们
Fighting it.
以为我们会一起取得胜利
That we'd all win together.
我们当时太蠢了
We were stupid.
你们不觉得你们现在也是在犯蠢吗
Y'all don't think you're being stupid right now?
你是说我应该杀了你吗
Are you saying I should kill you?
我是认真的  你会害我们吗
I mean it, are you gonna try and pull something on us?
我们手下留情是在犯蠢吗
Are we just being thick here by not removing all doubt?
此时此刻  我没有扣下扳机
Right now, by me not pulling this trigger,
是个错误吗
is that a mistake?
我是认真的  我真的想知道
I'm serious. I really wanna know.
你选择为其他人当杀手
You made a choice to kill for someone else,
为了能有个三尺之地遮风避雨就出卖自己
to have them own you for a roof over your head and three squares,
所以也许我没有考虑周全
so maybe I'm not considering all aspects here.
你告诉我  我是在犯蠢吗
You tell me, am I being stupid?
不是
No.
听着  我得去个地方
Look, I got somewhere to be.
我们可以做笔交易  我能帮你一把
We can make a deal. I can help you out.
你和他们是一伙的
You're one of them.
你受伤了  孤身一人
You're hurt and you're alone
为了活命什么话都说得出来
and you'd say anything.
我们一开始就不该相信你们的
We should've never trusted you people to begin with.
走吧
Go on.
继续走
Keep moving.
该死
Son of a bitch.
帕蒂
Patty.
她可能...
She could be...
(帕特里克燃料公司)
不  她不见了
No, she's gone.
只能另定计划了
Then we make another plan.
我们离开这里  这就是计划
Yeah, we get out of here, that's the plan.
那就这样吧
Then that's the plan.
你们没必要为我冒险
You guys didn't have to do this for me.
我们这样做是正确的
It was the right thing for all of us.
这是正确的吗
This was the right thing?
如果你们现在回去
Even if just you guys went back now,
说一切都因我而起...
if you just told them that it was me...
不  总会有办法的
No, we'll find a way.
-你们考虑一下  -不
- Just think about it. - No.
听着  或许我们走不了那么远
Look, maybe we don't get as far,
但我们会...
but we'll get-- hey!
蒂娜
Tina, hey!
妹妹  看着我
Hey, baby sister, look at me.
别跑  不
Hey, stop! No!
别跑  我们需要那东西  求你了
Don't! We need that, please!
萨沙  亚伯拉罕  能收到吗
Sasha, Abraham, are you there?
(胰岛素  需冷藏)
好了  安全
There, it's clear.
他的摩托不见了
His bike's gone.
这些是弹壳
These are shells.
他也有还击  逃走了
He fired at 'em, got away.
他受伤不轻
He caught a good bounce.
现在本来就人烟稀少
There aren't enough people around
难道还会有人故意埋伏吗
to just wait around for somebody to ambush.
他们也不可能跟踪我们
And they couldn't have just been watching us,
我们做的事很难被跟踪
not with what we were doing.
不  他们想干掉某些特别的人
Nah, they were looking to chew up someone in particular.
不管这帮人是谁
Whoever the hell they were.
达里尔  能收到吗
Daryl, you copy?
达里尔
Daryl?
我敢打包票  他肯定回亚历山大了
Dollars to doughnuts, he's on his way back to Alexandria now.
-他不会丢下我们的  -他这样做过
- He wouldn't leave us behind. - He already did.
但是他回来了
But he came back.
那我们去找他
So we go look for him.
寻找追踪者的最好办法是原地等待
The best way to find a tracker is to stay put.
让他来找你
Let him find you.
你想一直待在这里坐以待毙吗
You just want us to sit here with our precious leathers in our hands?
不
No.
(日出车险)
别去
Don't.
为什么
What?
你没那么蠢
You're smarter than that.
我们没必要暴露行踪
We don't need to leave bread crumbs.
(迪克森)
怎么不干掉这个帅哥呢
How come gorgeous over here is still standing?
它出不来的
He can't get out.
门锁了  我们没事的
It's locked. We're fine.
放哨或睡觉  随你选
Stand watch or sleep? Your choice.
我选前者
I'll take the former.
说不定再搜刮点东西
Do a little shopping, maybe.
(为曾做出贡献而骄傲  我为世界祈祷  坚持下去  保持乐观  咬伤会致死)
睡不着吗
Can't sleep?
你这不废话吗
What does it look like?
我只是想知道你是不是故意不睡的
I just wanted to know if it was a choice.
你不知道
You have no idea how much
我有多想消灭那家伙
I want to release that thing from this plane of existence.
这是我们的新家了吗
This our new home?
咱们应该给它起个名字吗
Should we give him a name?
一切都是你自己选择的结果
You got yourself into this.
本来该我独自开车  但你却要跟来
I was driving that car solo until you chose to come with.
那时我别无选择
Oh, I didn't have a choice there.
为什么
Tell me why.
你一个人去根本不行
You going stag was not an option.
为什么
Tell me why.
那时你失控了好一阵子
You were out of control for a good while there.
差点在去天堂的路上把我的胳膊卸下来
Just about took my arm off on the road to paradise.
-记得吗  -记得
- You remember that? - I do.
-我现在理智了  -我也是
- I'm in control now. - Me, too.
所以你想杀了那只行尸吗
That's why you wanna kill that walker?
街上那只
The one down the street?
还有车里那些人
The guys in the car?
因为你很理智
'Cause you're in control.
因为不了结一件事  让我如坐针毡
'Cause loose ends make my ass itch.
如果我心态不稳
If I have not gotten my psyche situated straight,
那也是因为麻烦始终不断地出现
it's because the shit's continually been hitting the fan without respite.
偶尔有间断  我们还开过派对呢
Oh, there's been respite. There was a party.
我记得
Oh, I remember that.
你那时很"享受"
You had the time of your life there.
你没必要跳出行驶着的车子
You don't have to throw yourself out of a moving car...
来让自己觉得在掌控中
to feel like you're calling the ball.
那很容易的
That's easy.
你跳下飞机
You jump out of an airplane,
之后就没有选择了
you don't have choices after that.
也许你可以挑战一下地面
Maybe you play some chicken with the ground,
可你拉开伞绳  就能活下去
but you pull the rip cord, you live.
但如果你头顶有屋顶
But if you have a roof over your head,
有食物  有高墙
you have food, you have walls...
你就有选择
you have choices.
没有行尸  子弹
And without walkers and bullets
和麻烦
and shit hitting the fan,
你就得负责
you're accountable for them.
我是说  该死  你一直都得负责
I mean, hell, you're always accountable.
只是有那么多噪音干扰
It's just with all that other noise,
你知道人们不会注意到的
you know people won't notice.
要么放哨  要么睡觉
Stand watch or sleep.
我选前者
The former.
守一整夜
Straight through the night.
我们早上再商讨
We'll reassess in the morning.
商讨什么
What do you mean?
我们还待在这干什么
What the hell we're doing here.
放下枪  放下
Drop the gun. Drop it.
给我
Give it to me.
我大老远过来
I came all this way.
你拿什么交换这个包
What you got for the duffel?
你让我受了太多罪  不能轻易给你
You put me through too much shit just to give it back.
这是我的原则
Principle of the thing.
你除了这把枪还有什么
What you got besides this gun?
没了
Nothing.
你在刻什么
What was that thing you were carving?
-我外公教过我...  -我不在乎  就它了
- My grandfather taught me how... - Don't care. It'll do.
拿走吧  都在里面
Take it. It's all there.
祝你们好运  你们会需要好运的
Good luck. You're gonna need it.
一了百了吧
Let's end this.
这是我们的
It's ours.
我们拿走的都是应得的
We earned what we took.
你们拿走的都得还回来
You're gonna return what you took.
来这里消耗的汽油以及
You're gonna pay for the gas it took to come out here
大家所费的时间也由你们买单
and for all the time these men took out.
结束了  你们知道规矩的
It's over. You know the rules.
狗屁规矩
Your rules are batshit!
我们才不回去  韦德  我们再也不下跪了
We're not going back, Wade. We're done kneeling!
别转移话题  混蛋
Don't change the subject, asshole.
快走  那边
Come on. Hey, that way.
快走  快  快
Come on. Go, go, go. Go.
起来
Get up.
拿去
Take it.
注意
Eyes open.
管好自己的区域  切换到A频道
You cover your quadrant. Go to alpha channel.
爱你  谢尔
Love you, Sher.
你们不用为我冒险
You didn't have to for me.
韦德  我被咬了
Wade, I'm bit!
-帮我砍了  -该死
- Take it off me. - Damn it.
动手  砍掉
Do it! Just take it off!
之后你的手表归我了
I'll get your watch after.
好了  就这样吧
All right, that's it.
该回家了
Time to go home.
卡姆受伤了
Cam got a boo-boo.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
是的  他不想继续了
Oh, yeah. He only wanted to take this so far.
他觉得强扭的瓜不甜
And he only wants ass that's willing, you know?
走吧  卡姆  走两步就好了
Come on, Cam. Let's walk it off.
我们以为你和他们是一伙的
We thought you were with them.
我们把你打晕  绑起来
We knock you over the head, tie you up,
还威胁说要杀你
threaten to kill you...
你为什么要回来
why the hell did you come back?
也许我也蠢
Maybe I'm stupid, too.
你们好啊  先生们
Well, howdy, gentlemen.
(唐娜·玛利亚)
火箭弹
Rpg.
你从哪里弄来的
Where do you get that?
这些都是
It is the fruit
我蠢得无可救药
of some off-the-chart stupidity.
去做傻事的时候得来的
Some grade-A, butt steak idiocy.
自知之明真是个好东西
Self-awareness is a beautiful thing.
是的
Yes, it is.
我了解这个团队
You see, I know this group
我了解瑞克
and I know Rick.
不管家里发生了什么事  肯定都得到了处理
And whatever happened back there is being managed
反正始作俑者没有好果子吃
and kicked right up into its own ass one way or another.
这点我知道
I know that.
我们有啤酒
We got beer...
空调
and air conditioning...
还有高墙
and walls.
我们这辈子都安排好了
The table is set for the rest of our lives,
但愿我们过得长久殷实
and I hope those years to be long and fruitful.
看到那样的时光...
I see that time before me...
让我一直有冲动想做点什么
and I've been feeling the urge to make some plays...
在死神随意夺走我的性命
before the great cosmic Pete comes to cut my throat unceremoniously
我咽下最后一口气之前
and I gurgle my last breath.
但在此之前生活还要继续
Well, things are gonna go on for a while before that,
我之前从来没有想过
and that hadn't occurred to me before.
我之前一直是走一步算一步
I've been kind of living check to check on that point.
我喜欢你看穿我的样子  萨沙
I like the way you call bullshit, Sasha.
我想更深入地了解你
I believe I'd like to get to know you a whole lot better.
那也是你想做的事之一吗
That one of your plays?
是什么让你觉得我想要被理解的
What makes you think I want that?
男人的直觉
A man can tell.
好吧
Well...
那你得先处理好自己的事
...you got some stuff to take care of.
没错
Yeah.
确实
I do.
所以你认识他们
So you knew 'em?
还觉得我是他们一员吗
Still you thought I was one of them?
尽管我们一开始就在那里
Where we were-- we were there since the beginning.
但依旧认不全所有人
We still didn't know everyone.
我们刚加入那会儿
Back when we first threw in with them,
那是个不错的地方
it was as good as a place as any.
之后生活变得艰苦  人们变得凶恶
Then things got harder, people got harder.
大家开始显露人性
Human nature kicked in and it became
上演了一出特别的闹剧
a truly unique kind of shitshow.
人们为了安全愿意交换任何东西
People will trade anything for safety,
为了知道他们是安全的
for knowing that they're safe.
所有东西
Everything.
最后他们一无所有  仅仅是
So they got nothing left except just...
活着
existing.
再也没人是安全的了
Hey, nobody's safe anymore.
不能跟人们那样保证
Can't promise people that anyhow.
你可以跟想听到那话的人保证
You could promise the people who want to hear it.
蒂娜  等等
Hey, Tina, hold up.
卡拉和德伊
Carla and Delly.
那是他们
That's them.
我和蒂娜在他们小的时候照看过他们
Me and Tina used to babysit them when they were kids.
所有人都说灾变发生时他们去北边了
Everyone said that they went out north when it all started.
我们不知道
We didn't know.
是我做的
I did this.
是我们做的
We did this.
抱歉
I'm sorry!
我很抱歉  宝贝  我们必须试试
I'm so sorry, baby. We had to try.
我们必须试试  我们必须那样做
We had to try. We had to.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我...
I'm...
喂
Hey.
你杀过多少行尸
How many walkers you killed?
-回答问题  -很多
- Just answer the question. - A lot.
至少几十只
A couple dozen at least.
你杀过多少活人
How many people you killed?
没杀过
None.
为什么
Why?
我为什么没杀过活人吗
Why haven't I killed anybody?
因为如果我杀了  就没有回头路了
Because if I did, there'd be no going back.
就永远无法回到过去了
There'd be no going back to how things were.
我来自的地方
I'm from a place
人们依然没变
where people are still like they were...
基本没变  不论好坏
more or less, better or worse.
我们从这里步行
I can walk it from here.
直到遇见我的朋友们
Till we meet up with my friends.
他们有车  你们可以坐他们的车
They got a car. You can ride with them.
你说你有多少朋友
How many friends you say there were?
我没说  他们有两个人
I didn't. There's two of 'em.
他们在哪里
Where are they?
我们去找找
We're gonna find out.
你怎么知道他们逃掉了  没被抓
How do you know they even got away? That they didn't get taken?
我不知道
I don't.
糟了
Oh, damn it.
对不起
I'm sorry.
把弩给她
Give her the crossbow.
你要回去吗
You gonna go back?
-你要安全吗  -闭嘴
- You gonna be safe? - Shut up.
再也没有安全的地方了
Ain't nowhere safe no more.
把弩给她
Give her the crossbow.
你要下跪吗
You gonna kneel?
包扎一下
Patch yourself up.
我们很抱歉
We're sorry.
你们会的
You're gonna be.
(帕特里克燃料公司)
(车牌号  帕蒂002)
瞧瞧我
Look at this.
怎么了
What?
没什么
Nothing.
瑞克  能收到吗
Rick, you copy?
有人吗
Anybody?
重复一遍
Say it again?
救命
Help.